# **Dan Carson**

okdan.com | dan@okdan.com | 425-802-2952

# Summary

An experienced designer who sincerely believes design can make a positive difference in people's lives. I am passionate about working with good people to find simple solutions to complex problems.

Most recently I was a Senior Designer at Modest, an early-stage mobile commerce startup in Chicago. As one of the first employees, I helped take the product from conception to launch over the course of a year.

Prior to that I hade the experience of a lifetime, as Lead Interactive Designer for Barack Obama's 2012 re-election campaign. I designed social organizing platforms, fundraising tools, and data visualizations that were used by millions of people and raised millions of dollars. I was named Design Director as the organization transitioned into Organizing for Action.

I am currently a freelance designer, working with great organizations like OpenGovFoundation, Hillary for America, Precision Strategies, Northwestern University, Planned Parenthood, and many more.

# **Experience**

### okdan.com

03/2015 - Present

Design consultant

Innovative, data-driven design that delivers results. Recent clients include Trunk Club, Change.org, AKPD Media, 270 Strategies, Precision Strategies, Planned Parenthood Action Fund, and the Democratic Party.

Modest, Inc.

02/2014 - 02/2015

Senior Product Designer

Senior Product Designer in charge of UX, interaction design, and user testing. I was responsible for the user experience of our native iOS and Android apps, new retailer on-boarding, and store management tools.

Change.org

07/2013 - 11/2013

Product Designer

Focused on the initial public launch of Change.org for Decision Makers - a revolutionary new tool that enables two-way dialog between elected officials and their constituents via the world's most popular online petition platform.

Trunk Club

02/2013 - 07/2013

Product Designer

Worked on a wide range of products, including optimization of the customer acquisition flow, redesigning the iPhone app, redesigning the public website, and helping implement brand guidelines across multiple platforms.

# Experience cont'd

#### Obama for America

Design Director

11/2012 - 02/2013

As OFA transitioned from a campaign to a non-profit I managed two other designers, and worked closely with our development and content teams to oversee the delivery of design products supporting the President's agenda.

#### Obama for America

10/2011 - 11/2012

Lead Interactive Designer

Worked alongside the most talented and passionate group of people I've ever had the pleasure of meeting. I collaborated every day with our field organization, technology, and digital teams to create tools and experiences that engaged with supporters, raised money, and earned votes.

#### Hornall Anderson Design Works

11/2009 - 09/2011

Interactive Designer

Interactive design and development, motion graphics, and thoughtful UX for clients like Madison Square Garden, Empire State Building, HTC, Microsoft, Pepsico, and Hewlett Packard.

**POP** 10/2006 - 05/2009

Designer and Frontend developer

I designed, built, and launched micro-sites, rich media banner campaigns, motion graphics, and 3d work for clients like Nintendo, EA, XBOX, Target, and Ubisoft.

**Squad Studios** 

03/2004 - 04/2006

Designer and Frontend developer

Designer, developer, and wearer of all possible hats. We built websites, music videos, and e-commerce products for some of your favorite bands.

# Education

## The Art Institute of Seattle

2002 - 2004

AAA, Interactive Media Development

Dean's List, Alumni Hall of Fame, and occasional speaker.

# Awards

1st Place at Hack4Congress DC, Seattle Show 2009, The FWA 2008, ADDY 2008, IAB Interactive Awards 2007